headhunter.com 2013-09-28

# Privacy Guidelines

We have updated our privacy policy to make it easier to read and understand. Now, Users can navigate directly from the Table of Contents to any privacy topic of interest. We also have eliminated several privacy policies that applied to specific products and have combined them into one privacy policy that applies to all products sold in the United States. Our revised policy also covers our recently developed products, such as our Work@ or NetworkEffect social network applications, and provides updated information regarding personal protection while job searching online. 

Please take a few minutes to read our updated Privacy Policy. These changes will take effect on February 1, 2013. 

### Effective Date: February 1, 2013

## Overview

CareerBuilder, LLC and its subsidiaries and divisions (collectively, “CareerBuilder", “We" or “Our") has drafted its Privacy Policy to ensure that you can clearly understand our data and security practices and policies as you use CareerBuilder websites and Apps (the “Sites"). This Privacy Policy describes the types of Personal Information we collect, how we use the information, with whom we share it, and the choices you can make about our collection, use and disclosure of your Personal Information. The phrase “Personal Information" refers to information that personally identifies you, such as your name, address, telephone number, email address, credit card number or other billing information. We also describe the measures we take to protect the security of your Personal Information and how you can contact us about our privacy practices. This Privacy Policy incorporates by reference the [Terms and Conditions](http://www.careerbuilder.com/JobSeeker/Info/HHTerms.aspx) for the Sites, which apply to this Privacy Policy. When you visit the Sites or provide us with information, you consent to our use and disclosure of the information we collect or receive as described in this Privacy Policy. 

Please review this Privacy Policy periodically as we may update it from time to time without prior notice to reflect changes in our data practices. We will post a prominent notice on our Sites to notify you of any significant changes to our Privacy Policy and indicate at the bottom of the notice when it was most recently updated. If we make material changes to the policy that will affect previously collected Personal Information, you will be notified and asked to consent to the updated Privacy Policy. 

Click on one of the links below to jump directly to the listed section:

  * Information We Collect
  * How We Use the Information We Collect
  * Information We Share
  * Resume Privacy Options
  * Cookies and Third-party Advertisers
  * Update Your Account Information 
  * Links to Other Websites
  * International Data Transfers
  * How We Protect Personal Information
  * Some Important Tips To Use When Dealing With Prospective Employers
  * California Residents
  * Children’s Privacy
  * How to Contact Us

### Information We Collect

We may obtain information about you from various sources, including our Sites, when you call or email us or communicate with us through social media, or when you participate in events, contests or other promotions. We also may obtain information about you from our parent, affiliate or subsidiary companies, business partners and other third parties and publicly available information.

The types of information we may obtain include:

  * Your Personal Information, if you choose to provide it or if we obtain it in the manner described above. You do not have to give us any Personal Information in order to perform job searches or to read the content portions of the Sites.
  * Username and password for the account you may establish on our Sites.
  * Payment details (including payment card number, security code, expiration date, cardholder name and billing address) if you buy products on our Sites.
  * Your demographic information (such as zip or postal code, occupation, education and experience, and if you choose to provide it, age, gender and race or ethnicity). We collect this information either through the registration process, from your resume or in the manner described above. 
  * Job search behavior and preferences, and a record of the searches that you make on our Sites. We do this in order to present you with job recommendations based on your interests as expressed previously through your searches. 
  * Other details that you may submit to us or that may be included in the information provided to us by third parties.

We collect information stored in your social media profile that you authorize us to access when you use your social media profile to enact features on the Sites, such as the ability to pre-populate our registration form or a job application, or the ability to see which of your friends have contacts with employers that interest you. CareerBuilder provides software applications (“Apps") available to the public, as well as Apps that may be purchased by companies for their employee’s internal use in talent management or as a company-specific social networking intranet. Through the use of these Apps, we may collect your social network data, but will never use nor share non-public social network data that you have restricted through your social network’s privacy settings. 

  * If you decide to download one of our Social Media Applications, such as Work@ or NetworkEffect, we will collect your profile information, including your social network site user ID, work email address, name, city, state, social network site profile image URL, and employment history, including job titles and company names. 
  * If you decide to download one of our Social Media applications, such as Work@ or NetworkEffect, we will also collect information about your friends and their connections. This includes, depending on your friend’s privacy settings, names, locations, and employment histories. 
  * Through use of the Work@ App, the individuals with whom you have a relationship on the social networking site may provide their contact information to you or directly to CareerBuilder’s customers when they request a referral or they apply for a job. CareerBuilder will collect the contact information of the individuals with whom you have a relationship on the social networking site in accordance with this Privacy Policy and the relevant terms of use associated with that social networking site. Depending on those individuals’ privacy settings, such information can include their social network site user ID, name, city, state, social network site profile image URL, and employment history, including job titles and company names.
  * When you use the Work@ or NetworkEffect App on your social network page or use the Work@ App on someone else's page, we may record information regarding the use of that Work@ App. 
  * If social network connections use the Work@ App to apply for a job or request a referral, CareerBuilder will collect those individuals’ names and email addresses and notify you about this activity.
  * When you invite individuals from your social network to use our Apps, make an introduction between individuals in your social network and other Work@ or NetworkEffect members, or send messages through the Work@ App, we collect and maintain the information associated with those messages, including email addresses and content.
  * We do not collect information on social media private messages that are not hosted by our App, unless we are a party to the message, such as when a user sends an app invite request.
  * Users of company-specific CareerBuilder products, such as the intra-net social networking app WorkLife, provide information to update and expand their employee social profiles and company-activity groups, in combination with basic directory information provided by your employer.

In addition, when you visit our Sites or use our mobile applications, we may collect certain information by automated means, such as cookies and web beacons, as described in more detail below. The information we may collect by automated means includes:

  * Information about the devices our visitors use to access the Internet (such as the IP address and the device, browser and operating system type).
  * Pages and URLs that refer visitors to our Sites, also pages and URLs that visitors exit to once they leave our Sites.
  * Dates and times of visits to our Sites.
  * Information on actions taken on our Sites (such as page views, site navigation patterns and job view or application activity).
  * A general geographic location (such as country and city) from which a visitor accesses our Sites.
  * Search terms that visitors use to reach our Sites.

(Return to Top)

### How We Use the Information We Collect

We may use the information we obtain about you to:

  * Register, manage and maintain your account on the Sites.
  * Provide products or services you request.
  * Process, validate and deliver your purchases (including by processing payment card transactions and contacting you about your orders, including by telephone).
  * Maintain a record of the jobs you view or apply to on our Sites. 
  * Inform you of relevant job postings that may be of interest to you.
  * Provide administrative notices or communications applicable to your use of the Sites.
  * Respond to your questions and comments and provide customer support.
  * Contact you and deliver information to you that, in some cases, is targeted to your interests (such as relevant services, educational or other career development opportunities); enable you to communicate with us through our blogs, social networks and other interactive media; and solicit your feedback and input. These communications will contain links for preference management and, where appropriate, unsubscribe links should you decide you do not want to receive further communications.
  * Manage your participation in our events and other promotions, where you have signed up for such events and promotions.
  * Operate, evaluate and improve our business and the products and services we offer.
  * Analyze and enhance our marketing communications and strategies (including by identifying when emails we have sent to you have been received and read).
  * Analyze trends and statistics regarding visitors’ use of our Sites, mobile applications and social media assets, and the jobs viewed or applied to on our Sites. 
  * Protect against and prevent fraud, unauthorized transactions, claims and other liabilities, and manage risk exposure, including by identifying potential hackers and other unauthorized users.
  * Enforce our Sites’ [Terms and Conditions](http://www.careerbuilder.com/JobSeeker/Info/HHTerms.aspx).
  * Comply with applicable legal requirements and industry standards and our policies.

We also use non-personally identifiable information and certain technical information about your computer and your access of the Sites (including your internet protocol address) in order to operate, maintain and manage the Sites. We collect this information by automated means, such as cookies and web beacons, as described in more detail below. 

If we seek to use the information we obtain about you in other ways, we will provide specific notice and request your consent at the time of collection.

(Return to Top)

### INFORMATION WE SHARE

When you apply for a job through the Sites or publicly post your resume to our resume database, employers will have access to information about you and your potential interest in employment opportunities. Those employers may use your information to contact you directly. Additionally, when you apply for a job through the Sites, the information supplied by you becomes part of the CareerBuilder database but also may become part of the employer’s database. Similarly, if your resume is downloaded by an employer, your resume may become a part of the employer’s database. In these instances, the use of such information by the employer will be subject to the privacy policy of that company, and we are not responsible for that company’s use of your information. 

Additionally, we may combine certain non-personally identifiable aggregate data about our users and use such anonymous aggregate data to prepare reports for our users (typically employers or educators). “Aggregate Data" is the demographic information (such as zip code, age, gender, race or ethnicity) and employment information (such as occupation, education and experience) of many individuals that is combined together. Aggregate data is used to analyze the characteristics of various populations and does not identify any specific individuals. For example, an employer may purchase a report from CareerBuilder that states the number of accountants with at least five year’s experience that live within a certain geographic area. All such reports sold only contain aggregate data which cannot be used to identify any individuals. 

We also provide reports about activity on our Work@ App that may contain identifiable information about users who choose to download and use that App. CareerBuilder’s customers that purchase the Work@ App will receive reports that contain the information collected through the Work@ App. The reports may include the following: the number of installations and removals of the Work@ App, the number of referrals, shares and wall posts made by you, the number of views and the names and email addresses of individuals with whom you have a relationship when they request a referral or when they apply for a job. CareerBuilder will not provide any other social network page content to its customers who purchase the Work@ App. Similarly, we will not share any non-public social network page content with employers, potential employers or others through your use of NetworkEffect. 

Information and communications on company-specific CareerBuilder products, such as the intra-net social networking app WorkLife, is accessible by your employer even where sub-group membership may be limited to employees with similar interests or employment duties. Information, communications and activities on the intra-net social networking app will also be subject to your employer’s internal policies and code of conduct in addition to this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use.

Other than instances where users opt to publicly post their Personal Information to our resume database, provide it via a job application, include it in a job posting or otherwise provide permission to share it, we do not sell our users' Personal Information to anyone for any reason. When posting jobs and resumes, our users decide for themselves how much contact information they wish to display. All users should be aware, however, that when they choose to display or distribute Personal Information (such as their email address or other contact information on a public resume) via the Sites or any other distribution method, that information can be collected and used by others. This may result in unsolicited messages, for which CareerBuilder is not responsible, from third parties. 

Where you have provided Personal Information on a Site that is ‘hosted’ or ‘co-branded’ by another company then that information will be made available to both CareerBuilder and the hosting/co-branding company. CareerBuilder is not responsible for what the hosting/co-branding company, or any third party with whom you may share your Personal Information, subsequently does with your information. You should review the privacy policy of the hosting/co-branding company to ensure that you are comfortable with how it intends to use and disclose your information. 

We also may share Personal Information with our service providers who help us in the delivery of our own products and services to you. These service providers may only use or disclose the information as necessary to perform services on our behalf or as otherwise required by law.

CareerBuilder also may disclose specific user information when we determine, in good faith, that such disclosure is necessary to comply with the law, to cooperate with or seek assistance from law enforcement, to prevent a crime or protect national security, or to protect the interests or safety of CareerBuilder or other users of the Sites. 

In addition, Personal Information we have collected may be passed on to a third party in the event of a transfer of ownership or assets or a bankruptcy or other corporate reorganization of CareerBuilder. 

(Return to Top)

### Resume Privacy Options

Posting your resume on the Sites puts you in front of thousands of employers with open positions each day. When you post your resume, we automatically create a registration for you using the email address and password that you supply. When you return to the Sites in the future you will use that same email address and password to access and edit your existing resume.

We know that our job seekers have varying levels of comfort when it comes to posting their resume on the Internet. To accommodate the needs of all users, CareerBuilder has 2 levels of resume privacy from which you can choose. Please note that these privacy settings only apply to whether or not your resume can be viewed by third parties. CareerBuilder will still collect, use or disclose anonymous, aggregated information about you and your visits to our website in the manner described in this Privacy Policy.

  1. ### Standard Posting

This option gives you the most visibility to the broadest employer audience possible by making your resume searchable in our resume database. If you select this option, any registered employer user who purchases access to the database can view your resume and contact details (to the extent you include them in your resume). 
  2. ### Private Posting For Apply Online Only

This option allows you to post your resume on the Sites without having it searchable by or viewable to employers. The benefit is that you can quickly and easily apply for jobs without retyping your information, and you provide your resume only to those employers you are specifically interested in.

We attempt to limit access to our searchable resume database to legitimate users such as paying employers, recruiters, hiring managers, headhunters and human resource professionals, but cannot guarantee that other parties will not gain access to this database. We cannot control the use of resumes by third parties who access such resumes while they are in our searchable database. You may remove your resume from our searchable database at any time. However, employers, recruiters and others who have paid for access to that database, as well as parties who have otherwise gained access to the database may have retained a copy of your resume in their own files or databases. We cannot control the retention, use or privacy of resumes or profiles that have been downloaded by third parties. Accordingly, you should not put information you would not want made public in your resume.

(Return to Top)

### About Cookies and Third Party Advertisers

A “cookie" is a text file that websites send to a visitor‘s computer or other Internet-connected device to uniquely identify the visitor’s browser or to store information or settings in the browser. A “web beacon," is also called a Web bug or a pixel tag or a clear GIF. Used in combination with cookies, a Web beacon is an often-transparent graphic image, usually no larger than 1 pixel x 1 pixel, that is placed on a Web site or in an e-mail that is used to monitor the behavior of the user visiting the Web site or sending the e-mail.

CareerBuilder uses cookies and other similar technologies for the convenience of our users. Cookies enable us to serve secure pages to our users without asking them to sign in repeatedly. CareerBuilder also uses cookies to store non-personally identifying information about you such as past jobs viewed and job searches conducted by your computer in a cookie that it places on your computer. We do this in order to present you with job recommendations based on your interests as expressed previously through your searches. Lastly, CareerBuilder uses cookies to ensure the proper functioning and efficiency of our Sites. Most Internet browsers enable you to erase cookies from your computer hard drive, block all cookies, or receive a warning before a cookie is stored. Please be aware, however, that some CareerBuilder features or services may not function properly without cookies.

CareerBuilder permits third party cookies on its Sites. For example, third party tools located on the Sites, including those that allow for social media sharing, may use cookies to remember user preference settings. CareerBuilder also uses web analytics services provided by third parties, which use cookies to collect non-personal information about details of our users’ visits to the Sites (including IP addresses) and the resources they access on the Sites. These third party web analytics services provide us with reports based on this information in order to help us understand how visitors engage with the Sites. 

We use third-party advertising companies who may place or access cookies on your computer hard drive to distinguish your web browser uniquely and to keep track of information relating to serving ads on your web browser, such as the type of ads shown and the webs pages on which the ads appeared. These companies may use information about your visits to these Sites and to other sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you on our Sites or on other, third party, sites. We also may give third party advertisers the ability to tailor their advertisements on our Sites using demographic and preference information we provide to them in aggregate form. This information does not identify you individually. 

These companies operate under their own privacy policies and CareerBuilder encourages you to be aware of the privacy policies of such companies. CareerBuilder does not have control over or access to any information contained in the cookies that are set on your computer by third party advertisers. 

To help prevent and limit the automatic collection of information by any participating third party advertisers, you may opt-out of such collection by clicking the Ad Choices icon located within the ad, by accessing the [“about ads" opt-out site](http://www.aboutads.info/choices), or by accessing the [NAI opt-out site](http://www.aboutads.info/choices). Please note that this opt-out is cookie-based. If you buy a new computer, change web browsers or delete this cookie, you will need to perform the opt-out task again. To obtain instructions regarding deleting or disabling cookies from third party advertising companies that are not members of the About Ads or NAI self-regulatory behavioral ad opt-out groups, please [click here](http://www.careerbuilder.com/Jobseeker/Page.aspx?pagever=remove-cookies).

In addition, some of the employers that use our Sites may place cookies on your computer through their job postings and may use such cookies to distinguish your web browser uniquely. Often, employers use such information to track the effectiveness of their job postings by measuring how many users who view their postings later became job applicants. To obtain guidance regarding deleting or disabling cookies, please [click here.](http://www.careerbuilder.com/Jobseeker/Page.aspx?pagever=remove-cookies)

(Return to Top)

### Update Your Account Information

You may access, update and amend Personal Information included in your online account at any time by logging into your account and making the necessary changes. You may also delete your resume from our resume database at any time by logging in to your account and deleting the resume. Deleting your resume will remove it from your account and from the resume database, however; if you have applied to a job in the past, that particular employer will still be able to access your resume. Further, you will not be able to delete data held by third parties, such as prospective employers, that have already accessed and downloaded your information or resume.

(Return to Top)

### Links to Other Websites

Our Sites may contain links to other sites for your convenience and information. These sites may be operated by companies not owned by CareerBuilder. In addition, if you are using our App through a social networking site, remember that our Apps may be served by or hosted by other sites. These other sites or linked third-party sites may have their own privacy notices, which you should review if you visit those sites. We are not responsible for the content of any sites not owned by CareerBuilder, any use of those sites, or those sites’ privacy practices.

(Return to Top)

### International Data Transfers

When we obtain Personal Information about you, we may process and store the information outside of the country in which you are located, including in the United States. The countries in which we process the information may not have the same data protection laws as the country in which you are located. Further, users who access your information, such as potential employers, also may be located in a different country than you and different laws may apply to their use of your information. 

CareerBuilder, LLC complies with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view CareerBuilder, LLC’s certification, please visit the U.S. Department of Commerce's Safe Harbor web site at <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>. You may also contact us directly to learn more about this certification.

In compliance with the US-EU and US-Swiss Safe Harbor Principles, CareerBuilder commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your Personal Information. European Union or Swiss citizens with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact CareerBuilder at [EU complaints.](mailto:eucomplaints@careerbuilder.com)

CareerBuilder has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the US-EU and US-Swiss Safe Harbor Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU SAFE HARBOR, operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed by CareerBuilder, please visit the BBB EU SAFE HARBOR web site at [www.bbb.org/us/safe-harbor-complaints](http://www.bbb.org/us/european-dispute-resolution/consumer/) for more information and to file a complaint.

(Return to Top)

### How We Protect Personal Information

CareerBuilder maintains administrative, technical and physical safeguards designed to assist us in protecting the Personal Information we collect against accidental, unlawful or unauthorized destruction, loss, alteration, access, disclosure or use. 

Please note that no electronic transmission of information can be entirely secure. We cannot guarantee that the security measures we have in place to safeguard Personal Information will never be defeated or fail, or that those measures will always be sufficient or effective. Therefore, although we are committed to protecting your privacy, we do not promise, and you should not expect, that your Personal Information will always remain private. As a user of the Sites, you understand and agree that you assume all responsibility and risk for your use of the Sites, the internet generally, and the documents you post or access and for your conduct on and off the Sites.

To further protect yourself, you should safeguard your CareerBuilder account user name and password and not share that information with anyone. You should also sign off your account and close your browser window when you have finished your visit to our Sites. Please note that we will never ask for your CareerBuilder account user name or password via email.

(Return to Top)

### Some Important Tips To Use When Dealing With Prospective Employers

  * You should use your own careful judgment about whether and what information to provide prospective employers.
  * DO NOT PUT SENSITIVE INFORMATION, SUCH AS YOUR SOCIAL SECURITY NUMBER, ON YOUR RESUME. 
  * CareerBuilder’s Sites are open to the public, and we cannot guarantee that all users of our services have a legitimate need to the information they seek. 
  * Do not provide your social security number, national identification number or any state, provincial or other local identification number to a prospective employer via online application. Identity thieves may attempt to trick you into providing sensitive information. Do not provide any non-work related personal information (i.e., your social security number or any other state or national identification number, eye color, marital status, etc.) over the phone or online.
  * Job seekers should never provide credit card or bank numbers or engage in a monetary transaction of any sort. 
  * Be cautious when dealing with contacts outside of your own country. 

For additional details regarding How To Spot Fraud Online, please [click here.](http://www.careerbuilder.com/JobSeeker/Info/privacy.aspx?version=fraud)

We use secure socket layer (or “SSL") technology to protect credit card transactions. The SSL technology encrypts credit card numbers while in transit so that they are not intercepted by unintended third parties. We use BluePay Processing LLC to process credit card purchases and their privacy policy may be viewed [here.](http://www.bluepay.com/privacy-policy)

(Return to Top)

### California, USA Residents

California law permits its residents to request and receive information about a business’ disclosure of certain categories of Personal Information to other companies for their use in direct marketing. If you are a California resident and a user of any of the Sites, you can request a copy of this information from CareerBuilder by sending an email to [customer.service@careerbuilder.com](mailto:%20customer.service@careerbuilder.com) or a letter to CareerBuilder at 5550-A Peachtree Parkway, Norcross, Georgia 30092, Attention: Customer Service. Please include your name and email address in email requests, and your name and postal address in mail requests. 

(Return to Top)

### Children’s Privacy

We do not knowingly collect or solicit information from anyone under the age of 13. If you are under 13, please do not use the Sites. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under the age of 13, we will delete that information as quickly as possible.

(Return to Top)

### How to Contact Us

You can direct questions regarding this Privacy Policy to CareerBuilder by emailing us at [customer.service@careerbuilder.com](mailto:%20customer.service@careerbuilder.com) or by letter to CareerBuilder at 5550-A Peachtree Parkway, Norcross, Georgia 30092, Attention: Customer Service. Please include your name and email address in email requests, and your name and postal address in mail requests.

(Return to Top)

CareerBuilder, LLC and its subsidiaries and divisions (collectively, “CareerBuilder”, “We” or “Our”) has drafted its Privacy Policy to ensure that you can use CareerBuilder’s sites on your own terms and completely anonymously if you so desire. CareerBuilder continues to strive to provide the safest possible environment for you to search for and apply to jobs.

## CareerBuilder Precautions

### Overview

We have created this Privacy Policy to demonstrate our commitment to protecting information you submit. This Privacy Policy only applies to data gathered on any web site under CareerBuilder’s control (collectively, the "Sites"), and does not apply to any other information or web site. Please review this Privacy Policy periodically as we may update it from time to time. This Privacy Policy is effective as of March 1, 2010. Each time you visit the Sites or provide us with information, you are, by doing so, accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy at that time. You agree that by using the Sites you are expressly and affirmatively consenting to our use and disclosure of the information that you provide, and consenting to receive emails, as described below.

### Personal Information

In order to operate the Sites in an efficient and effective manner and provide users with information on job postings and services that may be of interest to them, CareerBuilder may collect personal information, including contact information (such as an email address), from its users. In addition, this information allows us to provide users with private and secure areas to post and modify their original content on our Sites (e.g., jobs and resumes). We also automatically track certain information based upon your behavior on the Sites and use this information to do internal research on our users' demographics, interests, and behavior to better understand, protect and serve users in general. This information may include the URL that a user has just come from (whether this URL is on our Sites or not), the URL a user goes to next (whether this URL is on our Sites or not), a user's computer browser information, and their IP address.

You agree that CareerBuilder may use your personal information to contact you and deliver information to you that, in some cases, is targeted to your interests (such as relevant job postings, services, educational or other career development opportunities), or provides administrative notices or communications applicable to your use of the Sites. By accepting this Privacy Policy, you expressly agree to receive this information. If you do not wish to receive these communications, we encourage you to opt out of any further receipt by following the opt out provisions provided in each such communication. CareerBuilder may also aggregate certain non-personally identifiable information about its users (such as occupation, location, education and experience) and use such anonymous information to prepare reports that it provides to its users.

We do not sell our users' contact information to anyone for any reason if the user has indicated a desire for us to keep the information private. When posting jobs and resumes, our users decide for themselves how much contact information they wish to display (we enable private communication for those who choose to hide this information).

All users should be aware, however, that when they voluntarily display or distribute personal information (such as their email address or resume), that information can be collected and used by others. This may result in unsolicited messages from third parties for which CareerBuilder is not responsible. Also, you may have arrived at the Sites by following a link from a CareerBuilder newspaper affiliate or other affiliate. If so, please be aware that CareerBuilder may share your information with that affiliate and the affiliate may use the information consistent with its privacy policy instead of this one.

CareerBuilder may also disclose specific user information when we determine that such disclosure is necessary to comply with the law, to cooperate with or seek assistance from law enforcement or to protect the interests or safety of CareerBuilder or other users of the Sites. In addition, personal information we have collected may be passed on to a third party in the event of a transfer of ownership or assets or a bankruptcy of CareerBuilder.

### Credit Card Security

CareerBuilder employs encryption for secure credit card transactions.

### About Cookies and Third Party Advertisers

At CareerBuilder, we use cookies only for the protection and convenience of our users. Cookies enable us to serve secure pages to our users without asking them to sign in repeatedly. If a user's system is idle for more than an hour, however, the cookie will expire, forcing the user to sign in again to continue their session. This prevents unauthorized access to the user's information while they are away from their computer. You may have the ability to reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent; however, some CareerBuilder features or services may not function properly without cookies.

Third-Party Advertisers: We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit the Sites. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to these and other web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [click here](http://networkadvertising.org/consumer/opt_out.asp). 

### Safe Harbor

CareerBuilder has certified its adherence to the U.S. Department of Commerce's Safe Harbor Principles in connection with the U.S. implementation of the European Union Data Protection Directive. For more information about the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles and to view the certification for CareerBuilder, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce's Safe Harbor web site. You may also contact us directly at **(866) 438-1485** to learn more about this certification. In addition, CareerBuilder is a member of the BBB _OnLine_ U.S./E.U. Safe Harbor Dispute Resolution program. Please consult the BBB _OnLine_ website at www.bbbonline.org for more information concerning the BBB _OnLine_ privacy programs and dispute resolution procedures.

### What You Should Know

CareerBuilder cannot ensure that all of your private communications and other personal information will never be disclosed in ways not otherwise described in this Privacy Policy. Therefore, although we are committed to protecting your privacy, we do not promise, and you should not expect, that your personal information or private communications will always remain private. As a user of the Sites, you understand and agree that you assume all responsibility and risk for your use of the Sites, the internet generally, and the documents you post or access and for your conduct on and off the Sites.

## Protect Yourself

### Some Important Tips To Use When Dealing With Prospective Employers

  * Never give our your social security number to a prospective employer.
  * Never provide credit card or bank numbers or monetary transaction of any sort.
  * Be cautious when dealing with contacts outside of your own country.
  * Do not provide any non-work related personal information (i.e. social security number, eye color, marital status, etc.) over the phone or online.

### Other Privacy Features On the Sites

You never need to provide data to search for jobs. Logging into the Sites is always an optional task for you to take, (although logging in does give you access to smarter job search tools such as my careerbuilder, Personal Search Agents and Saved Searches.) 

### Post a Resume

Posting your resume on the Sites puts you in front of thousands of employers with open positions each day. When you post your resume, we automatically create a registration for you using the email address and password that you supply. When you return to the Sites in the future you will use that same email address and password to access and edit your existing resume.

### Resume Privacy Options

We know that our job seekers have varying levels of comfort when it comes to posting their resume on the Internet. To accommodate the needs of all users, CareerBuilder has 3 levels of privacy from which you can choose.

  1. ### Standard Posting

This option gives you the most visibility to the broadest employer audience possible by making your resume searchable in our Resume Database.

  2. ### Anonymous Posting

You can also post to the public resume database without any of your contact information being displayed. (If you use this option be sure to remove your contact information from the body of the resume.) The anonymous option also allows you to only display selected pieces of contact information.

  3. ### Private Posting For Apply Online Only

This option allows you to post your resume on the Sites without having it searched by employers. The benefit is that you can quickly and easily apply for jobs without retyping your information.

### Your General Contact Information

Managing your privacy is as simple as selecting which pieces of your contact information are displayed. This is done in the section of the resume form called "Contact Information." Using option 3 above requires that you select the Apply Online Only option from the "Contact Information" section at the bottom of the edit form, as shown below.

### Microsoft Windows Live™ ID

In addition to the CareerBuilder sign-in, CareerBuilder offers the ability to sign in using Microsoft Windows Live ID service, which provides authentication for online sign in. When you sign in to this site using the Windows Live ID service you will be asked to provide your e-mail address and a password to sign you in. This same Windows Live ID sign-in allows you to access many other participating Windows Live ID web sites.

## How To Spot Fraud

### Email and Online Fraud

Unfortunately, email and online fraud are continuing concerns for virtually all businesses that operate on the Internet. Please be aware that, from time to time, fraudulent emails have been circulated to CareerBuilder users that appear to be from CareerBuilder but which are, in fact, sent by imposters. CareerBuilder is not sending these fraudulent emails. If you receive an email or pop-up window requesting that you sign in to CareerBuilder and provide your personal information, do not respond.

This is an example of one such fraudulent email:

### Help Us Monitor Fraud

Please be advised that CareerBuilder will never initiate a request for your personal information via email or pop-up window. If you ever receive a request for this type of sensitive information, please do not respond and immediately contact CareerBuilder customer service at **(866) 438-1485** or report the suspected fraud using our [feedback form](http://www.fuzeqna.com/careerbuilder/consumer/question.asp).

If you think you have been a victim of fraud, immediately report the committed fraud to your local police and contact us using our feedback form so steps can be taken for your safety.
